#### Resume

http://coderbear.com/resume.pdf Seeking a Summer Internship for 2017

# Siddharth Anil Bhagwan siddharthabhagwan@gmail.com +1-(240)-917-9505

Over 6 years of experience as a web developer and experience designer around products and services. Currently pursuing my masters in HCI, while transitioning into Data Visualization and Big Data.

### Education

MS Human Computer Interaction, University of Maryland, Aug 2016 - May 2018 GPA 4.0

B.Tech Information Technology, PEC University of Technology, India, 2006 - 2010 GPA 6.93/10

#### **Skills**

Analytics - R Studio | Tableau | Jigsaw | Google Analytics

Design - InVision | Prototyping | Personas | Storyboarding | Wireframing | Balsamiq | Photoshop

Languages - JavaScript | Ruby | HTML | CSS | Shell Scripting | XSLT | Java

Libs, Frameworks & Db - React | Rails | Bootstrap | jQuery | Skrollr | Arduino | Postgresql

Tools & Protocols - Git | REST | SOAP | Grunt | Eclipse | WebSphere MB, MQ, DataPower

OS & Utilities - Mac OS | Unix | Windows | Travis CI | Heroku | AWS

## Work Experience

MS Human Computer Interaction, University of Maryland | Aug 2016 - May 2018 | College Park

Data Science - Using US DoE data to identify and predict admissions patterns

Analytics - Quantifying self efficacy in seeking health related information online in US for major races

CyberPsychology - Noticeability and impact of visual queues on USB 2.0 connectors

Design Methodologies - Redesigning the coach experience in flights for sleepers

DevToProd & Codemancers, Freelance Front End Engineer | Sep 2015 - April 2016 | Remote Design, development and performance benchmarking of front end modules using JavaScript.

Revealing Hour Creations, Software Engineer & Experience Designer | April 2014 - May 2015 | Pune, India 8 member hardware & software startup. Tah | Piano Stairs | Laser Harp | Doo | The Incarnate Word.

Lectito, Full Stack Web Developer | Mar 2013 - Mar 2014 | Remote

Complete design and development of Lectito, a platform to exchange books. Project dormant.

IBM, Systems Engineer for Enterprise Integration | Aug 2010 - Feb 2013 | Pune, India Middleware Engineer in EAI for Vodafone India. Design | Development | Testing | Go-live | Dev Ops.

#### **Achievements & Publications**

Memory Leaks in JavaScript - Speaker at India's first official jQuery Conf, 2015

Devmate - An open source ruby library with 4000+ downloads

Rudimentor - A web app for drummers to track their rudiments

Gitanjali - Most downloaded Android app for the Nobel prize winning poem 'Gitanjali' by Tagore

Auto Deployer - Shell script utility to automate Message Broker deployments, published in iRAM, IBM

Innovation Team Award, Eminence and Excellence Award - Awarded by the client Vodafone